so let's talk about problems or
centralized main memory and why we may
want to do something else as we have
seen in the previous quiz memory size is
a problem we need a large memory and
because it's all one big memory that one
memory will be slow and because of its
large size relatively far away from all
of the course we will also have the
problem of memory bandwidth because
message from all cores go to the one
memory so the requests from all of the
cores create contention for memory
bandwidth because a big slow memory will
have a limited bandwidth and what that
does is it prevents really additional
course from benefiting our performance
because all of the accesses are really
serializing in the queue waiting for
memory so if we add more cores that just
makes every course access is even slower
because they have to wait for memory
even longer so we don't really get a
performance advantage anymore so
centralized main memory because of these
problems works well only for relatively
small machines with something like 24 8
maybe 16 cores beyond this we saturate
the memory bandwidth and also our memory
needs to not be too big and too slow if
we keep it centralized